Phone: 617-901-6636 Email: lalit@bu.edu Webpage: Website / LinkedIn

Ph.D. economist with 8+ years in quantitative research, and 2+ years in healthcare investment banking. Expertise in economic analysis, financial modeling, and written and oral communication. Skilled with statistical analysis of large data, and mathematical modeling and calibration. Extensive experience with Python, R, Stata, MATLAB, and SQL.

Professional Experience

Doctoral candidate, Department of Economics, Boston University (Aug/2016-present)

- Executed end-to-end projects in international economics by first distilling questions from complex research, and then answering them through research design, data collection, empirical analysis, and interpreting results.
- Obtained private data from the World Tourism Organization; developed a quantitative model to show that easier access to visas can increase international trade between EU and China by 1.3%, and output in EU by 0.43%.
- Worked closely with other researchers to create a novel dataset tracking international expansions by scraping SEC's website; showed that serial M&A activity could significantly increase (>50%) market power of US firms.
- Showed that monetary policy could reduce the spillover of EU sovereign crisis to US; simulated monetary and fiscal policy in a dynamic model of international banking with geographical diffusion of credit default shock.
- Gathered unique data on Indian factories to show that large factories benefit more from IT adoption; developed a equilibrium model of scale-dependent production to account for non-linear returns to IT adoption.
- Synthesized results into accessible presentations to communicate at workshops and conferences.

Teaching fellow, Center for Data Science/Department of Economics, Boston University (2018, Jan/2021-present)

- Designed and delivered lectures for 3+ years to over 500 students, communicating with confidence and clarity.
- Covered a wide range of topics including econometric methods, time-series forecasting, and causal inference.
- Introduced Python programming, creating data pipelines, and deploying supervised and unsupervised learning models using the scikit-learn library and Kaggle datasets.

Consultant, World Bank, Washington D.C. (Summer 2019)

• Proposed a new measurement of poverty using realistic household demand to account for non-food consumption; highlighted the relevance of price index with simulations.

Investment Banking analyst/associate, UBS-Verity Knowledge Solutions, India (Jul/2011-Feb/2014)

- Developed deep knowledge of companies, their pipelines, and regulations across the healthcare sector; distilled it into original insights to create detailed pitchbooks and research reports for M&A advisory.
- Created relative and intrinsic valuation models including company comparables, and DCF models; automated the team's comps database update and reduce analyst burden from an entire day to under 3 hours.
- Extensive experience with financial databases including FactSet, ThomsonOne, Bloomberg, VentureSource, Factiva, and EvaluatePharma, as well as corporate releases including 10Ks/Qs, transcripts, and press releases.
- Communicated with clients, delivered on tight timelines, coordinated with team members, and mentored juniors.

Education

Ph.D. (Economics), Boston University, Aug/2016-Aug/2024 (Expected)

• Specialization: International-, Macro-economics; Graduate student fellowship (2016-2022)

M.Sc. (Quantitative Economics), Indian Statistical Institute (New Delhi, India), Jul/2014-May/2016

• First class with distinction (76%); Merit scholarship (2015, top 5 position in the cohort).

B.Tech. (Biotechnology), National Institute of Technology (Warangal, India), Jul/2007-May/2011

• First class with distinction (8.46/10); Indian Academy of Science—Summer Fellowship (2010)